<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Studio Code on Python Biella Group</title>
    <link>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Studio Code on Python Biella Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 20:10:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>linter installation</title>
      <link>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/installare-un-linter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:54:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/installare-un-linter/</guid>
      <description>As previously said, linter are your best friends for ensuring that everything is in order when writing the code.
To select a linter, go to the command line (press F1 or &amp;lsquo;ùCTRL + SHIFT + P or go to View &amp;gt; Command Palette) and type: &amp;gt; python: Select Linter . Select the linter that you want (we recommend flake 8).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make us of a Python version</title>
      <link>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/utilizzare-una-versione-di-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:54:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/utilizzare-una-versione-di-python/</guid>
      <description>When you open a.py file within a project, you will be prompted to choose a certain version of Python, which you can also see at the bottom right of vscode. It is possible to pick a Python version by pressing on the writing.
Always open the Command Palette (by hitting the F1 key or CTRL + SHIFT + P or typing View&amp;gt; Command Palette) and type: &amp;gt; python: Select Interpreter to choose the best Python interpreter for you ( for example your .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add tails to terminal</title>
      <link>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/aggiungere-code-al-terminale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:54:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/aggiungere-code-al-terminale/</guid>
      <description>A very interesting feature of Visual Studio Code is the addition of the command code file or folder&amp;gt; to the terminal, which opens a vscode window based on either file or folder on which you want to work (for example, by doing code. you may open the current cartella within vscode).
To do so, open the Command Palette and execute (closely) the following command: Shell command: Add the command &#39;code&#39; to the PATH</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>debugger usage</title>
      <link>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/usare-il-debugger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:54:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/usare-il-debugger/</guid>
      <description>It is possible to create a specific configuration of debugger settings for each project in order to debug on vscode and so launch different files.
Furthermore, while you are in the debug section, VSCode provides a tool that allows you to generate a specific configuration based on the framework or functionality that you are attempting to use via a template.
Using this procedure, a file called launch.json will be created within the project&amp;rsquo;s directory: .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing framework</title>
      <link>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:54:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pythonbiellagroup.it/en/visual-studio-code/testing/</guid>
      <description>After installing the Python extension, a new feature appears within VSCode: the ability to run tests through an interface with Python.
To use this feature, open the Command Palette and select Python: Configure Tests. From the list of test frameworks that will be displayed, choose your preferred framework (say pytest).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
